Finding Aid for Isle Royale papers, 1885-1955
Bentley Historical Library, University of Michigan
Isle Royale papers 1885-1955, 1921-1946
Detroit News.
(in 5 boxes)
2 linear feet
851553 Bb 2
Files of Detroit News conservation editor Albert Stoll and director of public relations Lee A. White. Correspondence, newspaper clippings, photographs, and miscellaneous papers relating to the Detroit News' campaign to make Isle Royale a national park and to secure land for it; manuscript and notes of an article by Martha M. Bigelow, 1955.
Bentley Historical Library, University of Michigan
The collection was donated by the Detroit News (donor no. 1011 ) in 1952.
No further additions to the papers are expected.
The collection is open to research.
In the 1920s and 1930s the Detroit News undertook a campaign to make Isle Royale a national park.
The collections consists of the files of Detroit News conservation editor Albert Stoll and director of public relations Lee A. White who directed the Isle Royale campaign. The collection consists of correspondence, photographs, clippings, speeches, and other materials relating to Isle Royale and to its importance to the state, and to the effort to make the island a national park.
Subjects:
Detroit news.; Isle Royale (Mich.); Isle Royale National Park (Mich.); Michigan. Isle Royale National Park Commission.; Upper Peninsula (Mich.); Natural resources.; American newspapers--Michigan--Detroit.
Subjects: Visual Materials
Airplanes.; Archaeological sites.; Brucker, Wilber Marion, 1894-1968.; Chapman, Oscar L. (Oscar Littleton), 1896-1978.; Civilian Conservation Corps (U.S.); Copper mining.; Couzens, James, 1872-1936.; Fishermen.; Fishing--Michigan--Isle Royale.; Forest fires--Michigan--Isle Royale.; Forests.; Hook, Frank Eugene, 1893-1982.; Isle Royale (Mich.); Kelly, Harry F. (Harry Francis), 1895-1971.; Laborers.; Marine accidents.; Mather, Stephen Tyng, 1867-1930.; Michigan. Isle Royale National Park Commission.; Mining.; Moose.; Aerial photography.; Postal service.; Resorts--Michigan--Isle Royale.; Ships--Great Lakes.; Stoll, Albert, 1884-; White, Lee A., b. 1886.
Contributors:
Albright, Horace M. (Horace Marden), 1890-1987.; Bigelow, Martha Mitchell, 1921-; Cammerer, Arno B. (Arno Berthold), b. 1883.; Chapman, Oscar L. (Oscar Littleton), 1896-1978.; Couzens, James, 1872-1936.; Cramton, Louis C. (Louis Convers), b. 1875.; Ferguson, William P. F. (William Porter Frisbee), b. 1861.; Grinnell, George Bird, 1849-1938.; Hook, Frank Eugene, 1893-1982.; Ickes, Harold L. (Harold LeClair), 1874-1952.; Kelly, Harry F. (Harry Francis), 1895-1971.; Mather, Stephen Tyng, 1867-1930.; Mershon, Wm. B. (William Butts), 1856-1943.; Moody, Blair, 1902-1954.; Newberry, Truman Handy, 1864-1945.; Oberholtzer, Ernest Carl, 1884-1977.; Osborn, Chase S. (Chase Salmon), b. 1860.; Ruthven, Alexander Grant, 1882-1971.; Shiras, George, 1859-1942.; Stoll, Albert, 1884-; Townsend, Charles Elroy, 1856-1924.; Tuttle, Arthur J., 1868-1944.; Vandenberg, Arthur H. (Arthur Hendrick), 1884-1951.; White, Lee A., b. 1886.; Wilbur, Ray L. (Ray Lyman), 1875-1949.
Genre
Photographs.
- Isle Royale files
  - Introduction (Box 1)
  - 1911-1919photos of 1885 shipwreck, scenery (Box 1)
  - 1921 correspondents include William B. Mershon, Truman H. Newberry, Chase S. Osborn, George Shiras, Charles E. Townsend, Arthur J. Tuttle (Box 1)
  - 1922photos of commercial fishing, scenery (Box 1)
  - 1923 correspondents include Arno B. Cammerer (Box 1)
  - 1924
    - January-February 1924 correspondents include Horace M. Albright, Arno B. Cammerer, George Grinnell, Stephen Mather (Box 1)
    - March-April 1924 correspondents include Arno B. Cammerer, Louis C. Cramton, Stephen Mather, William B. Mershon (Box 1)
    - May 1924 correspondents include Stephen Mather (Box 1)
    - June 1924 correspondents include Stephen Mather; photos of Stephen Mather inspection tour of island including scenery, group portraits, commercial fishing (Box 2)
    - July-December 1924 correspondents include Arno B. Cammerer, Stephen Mather (Box 2)
  - 1925 correspondents include Stephen Mather; photos of scenery (Box 2)
  - 1926 correspondents include Stephen Mather; photos of scenery (Box 2)
  - 1928 correspondents include Ernest Oberholtzer; photos of shipwreck (Box 2)
  - 1929photos of scenery, mines, commercial fishing, resorts (Box 2)
  - 1930
    - January-June 1930 correspondents include Horace M. Albright, Ernest Oberholtzer; photos of scenery (Box 2)
    - July-December 1930 correspondents include Arno B. Cammerer, Ernest Oberholtzer (Box 2)
    - Aerial photos: photos of airplane, scenery, resorts]: a full set of these aerial photos is found in the Map Library, 8th Floor Hatcher Library (Box 2)
  - 1931
    - January 1-March 15, 1931 correspondents include Horace M. Albright, Ernest Oberholtzer (Box 3)
    - March 16-May 31, 1931 correspondents include Horace M. Albright (Box 3)
    - June-December 1931 correspondents include Horace M. Albright, Arno B. Cammerer, Ernest Oberholtzer, Sen. Arthur H. Vandenberg, Ray L. Wilbur; photos of resorts, scenery (Box 3)
  - 1932 correspondents include Arno B. Cammerer, Alexander Ruthven (Box 3)
  - 1933 correspondents include Horace M. Albright, Arno B. Cammerer, Sen. Arthur H. Vandenberg; photos of shipwreck and survivors (Box 3)
  - 1934 correspondents include Arno B. Cammerer, James Couzens, Chase S. Osborn, Sen. Arthur H. Vandenberg; photos of James Couzens trip to island (Box 4)
  - 1935
    - January-April 1935 (Box 4)
    - May 1935 correspondents include Arno B. Cammerer (Box 4)
    - June 1-15, 1935 photo of Isle Royale National Park Commission (Box 4)
    - June 16-30, 1935 correspondents include Sen. Arthur H. Vandenberg (Box 4)
    - July 1-15, 1935 correspondents include Harold Ickes, Sen. Arthur H. Vandenberg (Box 4)
    - July 16-31, 1935 correspondents include Harold Ickes, Sen. Arthur H. Vandenberg (Box 4)
    - August 1-9, 1935 correspondents include Harold Ickes, Sen. Arthur H. Vandenberg (Box 5)
    - August 10-31, 1935 correspondents include Blair Moody, Sen. Arthur H. Vandenberg (Box 5)
    - September-December 1935 (Box 5)
  - 1936
    - April-June 1936 correspondents include Sen. Arthur H. Vandenberg; photos of forest fire and CCC firefighters (Box 5)
  - 1937 correspondents include include Arno B. Cammerer (Box 5)
  - 1938 (Box 5)
  - 1939 correspondents include include Arno B. Cammerer (Box 5)
  - 1940
    - February-July 1940 correspondents include include Arno B. Cammerer (Box 5)
    - August 1940photos of CCC work, post office interior, cruise ship, commercial fishing (Box 5)
  - 1941 (Box 5)
  - 1942 (Box 5)
  - 1943 (Box 5)
  - 1946
    - August 6-26, 1946 correspondents include Chase S. Osborn (Box 5)
    - August 27-31, 1946 speeches of Oscar L. Chapman, Frank Hook, Harry Kelly; photos of park dedication, cruise ship, Wilber Brucker, Albert Stoll, Harry Kelly, Frank Hook, Oscar L. Chapman (Box 5)
    - September-October 1946 (Box 5)
  - 1952 (Box 5)
  - 1955 notes and article by Martha Bigelow about Isle Royale National Park movement (Box 5)